Are you addicted to your smartphone?
你对自己的智能手机上瘾了吗？
Do you check your phablet in the middle of the night?
你会在半夜查看你的平板手机吗？
Do you post to social media as you stroll along the pavement?
你会在沿着人行道漫步时往社交媒体上发消息吗？
If you do the latter, you would be called a ‘smombie‘ in Germany.
如果你做了后者，在德国你会被称为“低头族僵尸”。
It’s a portmanteau word which combines ’smartphone‘ and ’zombie‘, and refers to the familiar sight of someone pottering along, eyes glued to the phone in their hand, oblivious to the world around them.
这是一个合成词，由“smartphone”（智能手机）和“zombie”（僵尸）组合而成，指的是人们常见的一种情景：有人慢悠悠地走着，眼睛紧盯着手中的手机，对周围的世界浑然不觉。
The term was chosen as Youth Word of the Year in Germany in 2015.
这个词在2015年被选为德国的年度青年词汇。
Indeed, just as mobile phones have changed the way we communicate, they’ve also enriched the stock of slang that describes human behaviour.
确实，就像手机改变了我们的交流方式一样，它们也丰富了描述人类行为的俚语库。
Another such term is ‘phubbing‘.
另一个这样的词是“低头症”。
Again, it’s a combination of two individual words, this time ’phone‘ and ’snubbing‘.
同样，这也是两个单词的组合，这次是“phone”（手机）和“冷落”。
Picture the scene: you’re out at a cafe with a friend, but instead of listening to your scintillating conversation, he‘s engrossed in his mobile phone.
想象一下这样的场景：你和一个朋友在咖啡馆，但是他没有听你妙趣横生的谈话，而是全神贯注于他的手机。
We’ve all been there.
我们都经历过这种情况。
Then there‘s a phrase which comes from Chinese: the ’bowed head tribe‘.
然后还有一个来自中文的短语：“低头族”。
This describes not a mere, singular smombie, but the legions of people we see stooped over mobile phones.
这个词描述的不是个体的低头族僵尸，而是我们看到的众多的俯身低头看手机的人。
And over in Japan, one blogger describes the groups of people dangerously traversing busy intersections as ’dumbwalkers‘, but who somehow manage to avoid crashing into each other.
在日本，一位博主把那些在繁忙的十字路口危险穿行的人群描述为“愚蠢的步行者”，但不知怎么地他们能够避免撞到彼此。
While many of these terms are light-hearted, there’s a serious side.
虽然这些词很多都带有轻松幽默的意味，但也有严肃的一面。
In the German city of Augsburg one phone user was killed after being hit by a tram as she crossed the road.
在德国城市奥格斯堡，一名手机用户在过马路时被有轨电车撞倒后身亡。
It prompted authorities to install ground-level traffic lights for those looking down at their phones.
这促使当局为那些低头看手机的人安装了地面交通信号灯。
And the risks with phones don‘t end there.
而且使用手机的风险还不止于此。
The desire for increasingly daring selfies has led to the deaths of over 120 people since 2014.
自2014年以来，对越来越大胆的自拍渴望已经导致了120多人死亡。
That’s more than have died from shark attacks.
这个数字比死于鲨鱼袭击的人数还要多。
It may come as no surprise to hear, therefore, that we‘re more addicted to our phones than ever before, according to a survey in the UK by Deloitte.
因此，根据德勤在英国进行的一项调查，我们比以往任何时候都更沉迷于手机，这个消息可能听起来并不令人惊讶。
Phones are our cameras, our calendars and our windows into the constantly updating lives of friends across social media.
手机是我们的相机，我们的日历，也是我们通过社交媒体了解朋友们不断更新生活的窗口。
Without our phones by our side, surely we’d miss out on all this fun?
如果我们身边没有手机，我们肯定会错过所有这些乐趣吧？
And yes, you guessed it, there‘s a slang term for that mentality too: ’fomo‘, or the ’fear of missing out‘.
是的，你猜对了，对于这种心态也有一个俚语：“错失恐惧症”，也就是“害怕错过”。